# ADAM VISOKAY

avisokay[at]uw[dot]edu  $\diamond$  website  $\diamond$  linkedin  $\diamond$  updated September 11, 2024

### SELECT PUBLICATIONS

From Narratives to Numbers: Valid Inference Using Language Model Predictions

2024
from Verbal Autopsy Narratives – Conference on Language Modeling (COLM)

LLM predictions from text narratives, then correcting inference to account for predicted data.

GPT Deciphering Fedspeak: Quantifying Dissent Among Hawks and Doves – EMNLP 2023 Is GPT-4 any good for a highly technical linguistic task using economic text data? Quantifying dissenting views on inflation among members of the US Federal Reserve Board since 1994.

# **EXPERIENCE**

Graduate Research Assistant, University of Washington, Seattle, WA 2024 -

Seattle Housing Authority - automating scrapers tools, maintaining ETL pipeline, analysis. 2024

Graduate Teaching Assistant, University of Washington, Seattle, WA 2023 -

Graduate Student Math Camp, STAT 221, SOC 110

# Independent Consulting,

2024 -

Washington State Center for Court Research (WSCCR) – built NLP pipeline to clean and model text data from court records to identify fine and restitution recipients by type.

Sound Data Project – created website with community info for the UW Puget Sound Survey project. 2024

Researcher, University of Washington, Seattle WA — R, STATA, Python

2021 - 2023

Advised by Professors Rachel Heath and Tyler McCormick.

Diffusion on networks, survey sampling, evaluating network formation models (LS, ERGM, SBM, etc.)

Research Assistant, Sciences Po, Paris, Remote — Python

Summer 2021

Primary data collection and feature engineering for Historical Migrations, Trade, and Growth (HMTG) project with Professor Thomas Chaney. Emphasis on ETL pipeline, NLP, entity matching.

# Professional Runner, Reebok

2018 - 2021

Track & Field distance runner representing the Reebok Boston Track Club internationally. Steeplechase.

# **EDUCATION**

| PhD Sociology, University of Washington, Seattle WA                | 2023 -      |
|--|-------------|
| MA Sociology, University of Washington, Seattle WA                 | 2023 - 2024 |
| MA Economics, Syracuse University, Syracuse NY                     | 2016 - 2017 |
| BA Economics & History, University of Virginia, Charlottesville VA | 2012 - 2016 |

### **SKILLS**

Methods supervised & unsupervised learning, inference with predicted data (IPD), deep learning,

vector embeddings, optimization, scraping, network modeling, MLE,

dimension reduction, visualization, probabilistic projection, bayesian HM,

Python networkx, nltk, spacy, bs4, TensorFlow, PyTorch, and Sklearn, keras

R igraph, Tidyverse, shiny, matrixSTATS, openNLP, IPD, torch Other STATA, Julia, LATEX, SQL, Apache Airflow, Docker, Azure

# **ACTIVITIES**

Home cooking, sourdough bread baking, pickle ball, camping and running (my best mile time is 4:02)